Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures Documenting Men's Lacrosse
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures documenting men's lacrosse
1965-2002
RU 966
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
107.75
(238 motion pictures)
The materials consist of 16 mm films and VHS videotapes documenting men's lacrosse at Yale. Also included is a 1968 Navy vs. Princeton game.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2004-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of 16 mm films and VHS videotapes documenting men's lacrosse at Yale. Also included is a 1968 Navy vs. Princeton game.
College athletes; College sports; Lacrosse; Motion pictures (visual works); Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Men's lacrosse game films, 1965-1976; Accession 2005-A-098
  - 1965-1966
    - Brown, 1965?; film reel (16mm) (Box 90)
    - Johns Hopkins, 1966 March 26; 4 (Box 1–4)
  - 1967-1968
    - Johns Hopkins, 1968 March 27; 4 (Box 5–8)
    - Navy vs Princeton, 1968 April 13; 4 (Box 9–12)
  - 1968-1969
    - Virginia, undated; 3 (Box 13–15)
    - Princeton, 1969 May 10; 4 (Box 16–19)
  - 1969-1970
    - Johns Hopkins, 1970 March 21; 2 (Box 20–21)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 20U)
    - Brown, 1970 April 25; 3 (Box 22–24)
  - 1970-1971
    - Penn, 1971 April 3; 3 (Box 25–27)
    - Navy, 1971 March 17; 3 (Box 28–30)
    - Cornell, 1971 April 1; 3 (Box 31–33)
    - Princeton, 1971 May 8; 3 (Box 34–36)
    - Johns Hopkins, 1971 March 21; 2 (Box 37–38)
  - 1971-1972
    - Army, undated; 3 (Box 39–41)
    - Brown, 1972 April 12; 3 (Box 42–44)
    - Penn, 1972 April 1; 3 (Box 45–47)
  - 1972-1973
    - Dartmouth, undated; 3 (Box 48–50)
    - Cornell, undated; 3 (Box 51–53)
    - Princeton, undated; 3 (Box 54–56)
  - 1973-1974
    - Harvard, undated; 3 (Box 57–59)
    - Army, undated; 3 (Box 60–62)
    - CWPost (Reel 1/3), 1974 March 20 (Box 63)
    - CW Post, 1974 March 20; 3 (Box 64–66)
    - Penn, 1974 March 20; 2 (Box 67–68)
  - 1974-1975
    - Cornell, 1975 May 4; 3 (Box 69–71)
    - Princeton, 1975 April 19; 3 (Box 72–74)
    - Dartmouth, 1975 April 12; 3 (Box 75–77)
    - Connecticut, 1975 March 22; 3 (Box 78–80)
  - 1975-1976
    - Penn, 1976 April 3; 3 (Box 81–83)
    - Harvard, undated; 3 (Box 84–86)
    - Brown, 1976 April 10; 3 (Box 87–89)
- Men's lacrosse game videotapes, 1984-2002; Accession 2006-A-032
  Scope and Contents
  Scores in parentheses.
  - Penn (7-10), 1984; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Penn (12-11), 1985; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Brown (6-7), 1985; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - University of Massachusetts (6-10), 1986; videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Cornell, 1986; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Army (6-17), 1986; videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Penn, 1986; videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Brown (7-13), 1986; 2 (Box 8–9)
  - New Hampshire (16-11), 1987; videotape (VHS) (Box 10)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 10U)
  - Army (10-11), 1987; videotape (VHS) (Box 11)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 11U)
  - Delaware (16-6), 1987; videotape (VHS) (Box 12)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 12U)
  - University of Massachusetts (8-16), 1987; videotape (VHS) (Box 13)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 13U)
  - Cornell (6-16), 1987; videotape (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 14U)
  - New Hampshire, 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 15)
  - Penn (12-11), 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 16)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 16U)
  - Harvard, 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 17)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 17U)
  - Delaware (10-5), 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 18)
  - Brown versus White (6-9), 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 20)
  - Penn (8-14), 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 21)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 21U)
  - Dartmouth (10-7), 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 22)
  - Harvard (11-3), 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 23)
  - Army (13-6), 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 24)
  - Boston College (22-6), 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 25)
  - Aldelphi, 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 26)
  - Princeton (10-8), 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 27)
  - Loyola: college lacrosse semi-finals, 1990; videotape (VHS) (Box 28)
  - Cornell, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 29)
  - Delaware (12-10), 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 30)
  - Harvard, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 31)
  - Pennsylvania, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 32)
  - Army, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 33)
  - Princeton (8-17), 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 34)
  - Virginia (6-13), 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 35)
  - St. Johns (13-8), 1991 March 13; videotape (VHS) (Box 36)
  - Brown (5-11), 1991 April 11; videotape (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Duplicating Master, 8
    - Use copies, 1; and 1 optical disk (DVD) (Box 37U1–37U2)
  - Army, 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 38)
  - Brown, 1991 September 22; videotape (VHS) (Box 39)
  - University of Massachusetts (5-6), 1991; videotape (VHS) (Box 40)
  - Hofstra (10-4), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 41)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 41U)
  - Dartmouth (17-6), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 42)
  - Army (12-11), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 43)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 43U)
  - University of Massachusetts (7-8), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 44)
  - Brown (7-9), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 45)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 46)
  - Princeton (6-14), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 47)
  - St. Johns (12-10), 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 48)
  - Harvard, 1992; videotape (VHS) (Box 49)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 49U)
  - Joseph Brooks Stratmore II, 1992 February; videotape (VHS) (Box 50)
  - St. Johns (9-6), 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 51)
  - Pennsylvania, 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 52)
  - Cornell (11-8), 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 53)
  - Massachusetts (13-14), 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 54)
  - Army, 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 55)
  - Harvard, 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 56)
  - Delaware, 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 57)
  - Pennsylvania, 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 58)
  - Hofstra (9-6), 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 59)
  - Cornell (8-11), 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 60)
  - Pennsylvania, 1994; videotape (VHS) (Box 61)
  - Princeton, 1994; videotape (VHS) (Box 62)
  - Syracuse, 1994 March 11; videotape (VHS) (Box 63)
  - Army (7-8), 1994; videotape (VHS) (Box 64)
  - Brown (3-5), 1994; videotape (VHS) (Box 65)
  - Pennsylvania, 1994; videotape (VHS) (Box 66)
  - Princeton (6-10), 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 67)
  - Cornell (12-10), 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 68)
  - Brown (8-12), 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 69)
  - Pennsylvania, 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 70)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    The video recording is available in digital form from Manuscripts and Archives.
  - Syracuse, 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 71)
  - Maryland, 1995 April; videotape (VHS) (Box 72)
  - University of Massachusetts (2-6), 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 73)
  - Pennsylvania, 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 74)
  - Vermont (9-5), 1995; videotape (VHS) (Box 75)
  - UMass, 1996; videotape (VHS) (Box 76)
  - Princeton, 1996; videotape (VHS)
    Custodial History
    Box 77 was deaccessioned on 2016-03-28.
  - Delaware, 1996; videotape (VHS) (Box 78)
  - Delaware, 1996; videotape (VHS) (Box 79)
  - Army, 1996; videotape (VHS) (Box 80)
  - Brown, 1997; videotape (VHS) (Box 81)
  - Dartmouth, 1997; videotape (VHS) (Box 82)
  - Syracuse, 1997; videotape (VHS) (Box 83)
  - PSV, 1997; videotape (VHS) (Box 84)
  - Boston College, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 85)
  - Dartmouth, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 86)
    - Duplicating master, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 86D)
  - TSV, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 87)
  - Drexel, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 88)
  - Vermont, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 89)
  - Cornell, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 90)
  - Delaware, 1998; videotape (VHS) (Box 91)
  - Delaware (10-9), 1999; videotape (VHS) (Box 92)
  - Fairfield (13-8), 1999 February 19; videotape (VHS) (Box 93)
  - Maryland (o/d), 1999; videotape (VHS) (Box 94)
  - Princeton (5-10), 1999 April 3; videotape (VHS) (Box 95)
  - Cornell (7-6), 1999 March 27; videotape (VHS) (Box 96)
  - Penn (2-7), 1999 March 20; videotape (VHS) (Box 97)
  - Syracuse (9-15), 1999 March 13; videotape (VHS) (Box 98)
  - Colgate (8-11), 1999 March 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 99)
  - Rutgers (9-10), 1999 April 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 100)
  - Brown (9-8), 1999 April 7; videotape (VHS) (Box 101)
  - Maryland, 1999; videotape (VHS) (Box 102)
  - Towson, 1999 April 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 103)
  - Dartmouth (10-5), 1999 April 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 104)
  - Boston College, 1999 April 19; videotape (VHS) (Box 105)
  - Colgate (8-11), 1999 March 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 106)
  - Harvard, 1999 April 24; videotape (VHS) (Box 107)
  - Princeton (o/d), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 108)
  - Penn (11-10), 2000 March 18; videotape (VHS) (Box 109)
  - Princeton (5-17), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 110)
  - Cornell, 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 111)
  - Drexel, 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 112)
  - Princeton (d/o), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 113)
  - Colgate (9-5), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 114)
  - Brown, 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 115)
  - Hofstra, 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 116)
  - Rutgers (19-16), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 117)
  - Boston College (15-6), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 118)
  - Harvard (14-5), 2000; videotape (VHS) (Box 119)
  - Albany, 2000 April 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 120)
  - Brown (7-14), 2000 April 5; videotape (VHS) (Box 121)
  - Colgate, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 122)
  - Duke, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 123)
  - Drexel (8-10), 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 124)
  - Penn (13-8), 2001 March 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 125)
  - Dartmouth, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 126)
  - Albany (16-4), 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 127)
  - University of Massachusetts (7-14), 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 128)
  - Brown, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 129)
  - Maryland, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 130)
  - Hobart/Delaware, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 131)
  - Harvard (9-7), 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 132)
  - Lehigh, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 133)
  - Cornell, 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 134)
  - Quinnipiac (17-8), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 135)
  - Delaware (scrimmage), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 136)
  - Brown (8-9), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 137)
  - Stony Brook (scrimmage), 2002 March 23; videotape (VHS) (Box 138)
  - Harvard (6-5), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 139)
  - Duke (6-11), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 140)
  - Stony Brook (scrimmage), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 141)
  - Drexel, 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 142)
  - Maryland (Coach Stainbrook) [commercially-produced], 2002 April 26; videotape (VHS) (Box 143)
  - Albany (13-7), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 144)
  - Penn (11-5), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 145)
  - Dartmouth (12-5), 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 146)
  - Sacred Heart/Drexel, circa 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 147)
  - Pennsylvania State, circa 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 148)
  - Stony Brook, circa 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 149)
  - Yale Fall Classic, 2002; videotape (VHS) (Box 150)